<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Jack&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Jack&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:07:58 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyric Mood Classification</title>
      <link>https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/lyric-mood-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:07:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/lyric-mood-classification/</guid>
      <description>For this project, my team and I attempted to classify the &amp;ldquo;mood&amp;rdquo; of song lyrics with a Convolutional Neural Network. We achieved a classification accuracy of 77%. Other published research works with heavily engineered SVM models scored less than 70%.
FYI - this page is a work-in-progress Motivation This project was completed as part of UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Masters of Information and Data Science (MIDS) program in the course &amp;ldquo;W266 Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifter Clustering and Lift Classification</title>
      <link>https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/lifter-clustering-and-lift-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 16:57:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jackcworkman.com/blog/portfolio/lifter-clustering-and-lift-classification/</guid>
      <description>How can data science be applied to the weight room? Chances are, you or someone you know are a member of a gym or an athletic club and lift weights periodically. Numerous companies provide gym membership benefits to their employees or host weight rooms on their campuses. Weight lifting is pervasive: it is used by both casual and professional athletes as part of their training programmes. With all of these people lifting weights, there must be some rich, analyzeable data out there for data scientists to play with, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>